上の妹　阿良々木火憐　中学三年生
My older little sister, Araragi Karen,
is a third-year in middle school.
六月末に誕生日を迎えて十五歳
She turned fifteen at the end of June.
She's always been a tomboy who excels at sports.
子供の頃から　運動が得意な活発なやつではあったが
その才能はどうやら戦闘行為にこそ向いていたらしく
But her talents seem best suited for combat.
あっという間に　空手の黒帯を取った
She earned her black belt in record time.
その姿は嵌り過ぎていてあんまり　女の子と言う感じではない
She enjoys fighting too much
to appear truly feminine.
I wouldn't call her manly,
男勝りとまでは言わないが　攻撃的な吊り目も手伝って
but the aggressive look in her eyes
makes her appear boyish.
どこかボーイッシュなのだ
続いて　下の妹　阿良々木月火　中学二年生
And my younger little sister, Araragi Tsukihi,
is a second-year in middle school.
Her birthday was in early April,
誕生日は四月の頭で　つまり現在十四歳
making her fourteen.
火憐はなんと言うか　外見通りの中身なのだが
Karen is, well,
exactly what she looks like.
But Tsukihi's appearance contradicts her true nature.
月火は　外見が中身を裏切っている
中身が外見を裏切っているわけじゃないところがミソだ
However, what's important is that her true nature
does not conflict with her appearance.
She looks extremely feminine,
外見はいかにも女子女子しているが
しかしその内面は火憐以上に攻撃的で　しかも怒りっぽい
but her nature is even more aggressive than Karen's.
And she's easily provoked.
Her fits could almost be called hysterics.
その怒りっぽさは　もはやヒステリーと言ってもいいレベルである
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
The Fire Sisters of Tsuganoki 2nd Middle School...
栂の木二中のファイヤーシスターズ
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
The pair has formed what could be considered
二人は　お助け隊と言うか世直し組と言うか
either a rescue squad or a heroic duo,
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
なんかそんな正義の味方ごっこを日常的に繰り返しているそうだ
a game that occupies the majority of their time.
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
Of course, were you to tell them that...
勿論　そんなことを彼女たちに言えば
It isn't a game, Nii-chan!
ごっこじゃないよ　兄ちゃん
We aren't allies of justice.
正義の味方じゃなくて正義そのものだよ　お兄ちゃん
We're justice itself, Onii-chan.
They'd reply like that.
と言うに決まっている
I can usually anticipate what they'll say.
あいつらの言いそうなものは大体わかるのだ
But I can say this without hesitation...
しかし僕は声を大にして言うことができる
Araragi Karen and Araragi Tsukihi,
阿良々木火憐と阿良々木月火
the actions of the Fire Sisters
彼女達　ファイヤーシスターズの行為は
are nothing but a game.
やはり　正義の味方ごっこでしかないのだと
Because, my dear little sisters,
僕の自慢の妹達　お前達はどうしようもなく　偽物なのだと
you are irredeemable fakes.
My older little sister.
Araragi Karen.
Since elementary school, her hair was mostly in a ponytail.
If I recall, there was this one time, though, when she had just entered middle school that she dyed her hair.
She dyed it such a shocking, glaring pink that it could not even be compared to an anime character's.
To this day, her reason for doing that is still unknown. However, what consequently followed was predictable.
Our mother slapped her across her face. (In her defense, that was probably the one time when she lost her temper and took physical punishment with her children.)
That same night, Karen dyed her hair back to normal black (with Indian ink).
However, she continued to follow up her infamous middle school impression, and it's understandable how that affected her personality.
Quite plainly, she isn't what one would call "cute".
"Cool" would fit better.
For a while now, Karen has been training in martial arts, and has consequently achieved great posture.
Because of this, she seems to be a significant five centimeters taller than she really is.
This appearance also appears to be a reason for her to never wear any skirts.
She claims,"My legs would seem too long with a skirt on," while she leaves for school wearing her favorite, loose jersey.
She probably is the only one who can still look cool while wearing an outfit like that.
Karen Bee Part 2
Episode 2
Type Font Used HGP Minchou B
Sengoku, that's how you do it at home?
千石　家ではそうなのか
えっ　えと
そ…そうって　どう
D-Do what?
Those bangs.
いや　ほら　その前髪
B-Bangs?
ま…前髪　な…何のことかな
Wh-What are you talking about?
She's feigning ignorance.
とぼけた
I-I definitely didn't work up the courage
べ　べ…別に　暦お兄ちゃんが初めてうちに遊びに来てくれるんだからって
to change my hairstyle because you were
勇気を振り絞ったりなんて　撫子　してないよ
coming over to my house for the first time.
Come in, Koyomi-oniichan.
さ　暦お兄ちゃん　あがってあがって
Sure...
あれ
Hey, Sengoku...
千石　お父さんかお母さんは
Where are your mom and dad?
うちの親　土曜日も勤めに出てるの
My parents work on Saturdays.
へえ　じゃあ僕の家と一緒だ　だから電話には千石が出たのか
Just like mine.
So that's why you answered the phone.
My room is on the second floor.
撫子の部屋　二階だから
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
Sengoku, that clo—
千石　あのクロー…ゼット
開けないで
Don't open it!
—set...
I'd never forgive anyone, even you, for opening it.
開けたら暦お兄ちゃんでも許さないから
Okay, have a seat there,
じゃ　暦お兄ちゃん　そこに座って
Koyomi-oniichan.
There? On the bed?
そこって　ベットの上か　いいのか
You sure?
Yeah.
うん　ベットの上以外に座ったら駄目
You can't sit anywhere but on the bed...
ふ　ふう　この部屋　何だか熱いよね
This room is kind of hot, isn't it?
こ…暦お兄ちゃんもそのバーカーを脱いだらどう
Wh-Why don't you take off your
sweatshirt, Koyomi-oniichan?
ん　僕か
Me?
Even if you aren't hot,
you still have no choice
暑くなくとも　暦お兄ちゃんはそのバーカーを脱ぐ以外ないんだよ
but to remove your sweatshirt.
I have no choice but to remove it, huh?
脱ぐ以外ないとは
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
Koyomi-oniichan, let's play the King Game.
暦お兄ちゃん　王様ゲームしよう
Sengoku, do you even know what a King Game is?
千石　そもそもお前　王様ゲームって何か知ってるのか
トランプのキングは何も関係ないんだぞ
It has nothing to do with a deck of cards.
I know what it is.
知ってるよ　船長さんの命令みたいなものでしょう
It's like a captain's orders, right?
SIMON
SAYS
The king's word is law!
王様の言うことは　接待
Too political!
政治的過ぎる
まあ　僕もやったことがないから詳しくは知らないけれど
Well, I've never played one before,
so I don't really know.
But, Sengoku,
千石　王様ゲームって多分二人でやるような遊びじゃねえたろう
you can't have a King Game with just two players.
Why not?
なんで　撫子は別にどっちも平気だよ
I'm fine with either role.
命令するのも　されるのも
Giving the orders or taking them.
W-Well, let's not play that...
まあ　王様ゲームはやめておこう
Then let's play the Game of Life, Koyomi-oniichan.
じゃ　人生ゲームしようか　暦お兄ちゃん
The Game of Life, huh?
人生ゲームか　うん　いいな
Sure, that sounds fun.
The word of Life is law!
人生の言うことは　絶対
Deep!
深っ
I
II
The Legend
of
Princess Kaguya
I
III
II
Japanese Chronicles
The Pillow Book
Census of the Lands
The Floating World 1
The Floating World 2
Anthology of Past Tales
Humorous & Crazy Poems   1
Humorous & Crazy Poems   2
Humorous & Crazy Poems   3
Ihara Saikaku's Poems      1
Ihara Saikaku's Poems      2
Puppet Plays of Chikamatsu       1
Puppet Plays of Chikamatsu       2
Puppet Plays of Chikamatsu       3
Introduction to Classics         1
Introduction to Classics         2
Modern Waka I
Modern Waka II
Modern Haiku Anthology
18 Kabuki Plays
Past & Present Authors 1
Past & Present Authors 2
History's Story   1
History's Story   2
History's Story   3
Complete Commentary Catalog
The continuation of learning
A Writer's Diary
Of the Crescent Moon
Collection of Ten Thousand Leaves
Furai Sanjin's Compilation
Tales of Genji
Tale of the Hollow Tree
Waka for All Ages
Of Phantoms and Apparitions
o
Ueda Shuusei's Poems   Part 1
Ueda Shuusei's Poems   Part 2
Basho's Anthology
Basho's Poetry Collection
Chronicles  3
Chronicles  2
Chronicles  1
Tales of Heike
Tales of Uji    3
Tales of Uji
Hermit's Collections: Golden Pagoda Tree Archives
The Ten Foot Square Hut
Kabuki Scenario Compilations       1
Kabuki Scenario Compilations       2
Vale of Tears      2
Vale of Tears      1
Oh, yeah.
あ　そうだ　それこそ昔
An Unasked-for Tale  3
An Unasked-for Tale  2
An Unasked-for Tale  1
Issa's Compilations
Tales of Heiji
Ancient Stories      2
Ancient Stories      1
Tales of Hougen
If I Could Exchange Them! Story
Tales of Sumiyoshi
Murasaki Shikubu's Diary      2
Murasaki Shikubu's Diary      1
The Eternal Storehouse Japan
II
I
Five Women Who Loved Love
The Life of an Amorous Man
The Life of an Amorous Woman
Tales of Ise Part     2
Tales of Ise Part     1
Tales of Heike II
Tales of Heike I
The Great Mirror
Ancient and Modern Poems
1  2
Humorous and Crazy Poems II
Humorous and Crazy Poems I
Story by Anonymous
1   2
Tale of the Hollow Tree
Yoshitsune's Records II
Yoshitsune's Records I
Census of the Lands      3
Census of the Lands          2
Census of the Lands
Diary of Sarashina II
Diary of Sarashina I
Annals of the Great Peace III
Annals of the Great Peace II
Annals of the Great Peace I
Tosa's Diary II
Tosa's Diary I
Diary of Izumi Shikibu II
Diary of Izumi Shikibu I
Wakefulness at Night
Bassho's Anthology
Kyougen Collection
New Collection of Ancient & Modern     Poems
Sand and Pebbles     II
Sand and Pebbles     I
The Lotus Sutra
I
II
Chikamatsu Monzaemon's Collection 3
Chikamatsu Monzaemon's Collection 2
Chikamatsu Monzaemon's Collection 1
Tales of Yamato
III
II  I
Eigamonogatari
We used to play that at my place, right?
僕の家に一緒にやったことがあるんじゃないか
うん　憶えてるよ
Yeah, I remember.
そっか
Yeah?
I never forgot.
そもそも忘れたことがない
Koyomi-oniichan will not get dirty thoughts
暦お兄ちゃんは　千石の身体を見でも　いやらしい気持ちになったりはしない
from looking at Sengoku's body.
僕が紳士でよかったな　千石
Aren't you glad I'm such a gentleman, Sengoku?
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
Time
Passes
Sengoku, has anything been happening lately?
千石　最近なんか変わったことないか
えっ　どういう意味かな
Wh-What do you mean?
I mean anything like what happened before.
いや　この間みたいなことはないかって
ううん　撫子は別に
No, I've been fine.
I see.
そっか
But there's some weird spell
circulating, as usual.
でも相変わらず　変な「おまじない」ははやってるみたいだけれど
At your school?
千石の学校でか
Yeah, but not just my school.
そうだけど　うちの学校だけじゃなくて　中学生の間全般で
Among all the middle schools.
I think Rara-chan and the others
are up to something.
多分　ららちゃん達が今　なんかしてる
"Up to something?"
なんかしてる
When I talked to her a while ago,
こないだ　ららちゃんに話…こないだの蛇のはなしを聞かれたし
she asked about what happened with the snake.
And since I couldn't tell her the truth,
まさか本当のことを話すわけにはないから　中途半端な感じになっちゃったけど
I didn't say much.
But she was getting others to
help her investigate stuff.
でも　人の手とか借りて　色々調べてたみたい
In other words,
つまり　例の「おまじない」関係ってことだよな
it has to do with that spell.
でも　そもそもあれって正確に言えば呪いとしてはガセみたいなもんなんだろ
But to be precise, that whole
curse was basically nonsense, right?
千石の場合は　むしろ千石の対処がまずかったってだけで
In your case, you just chose the
wrong way to handle it.
Yeah.
うん　怪異が本当に　正真正銘あそこまでの形で実現したのなんて
I was the only one
for whom anything actually
manifested that way, I think.
撫子の場合だけだと思うよ　多分だけど
But that's just a guess.
Then...
だったら
But I don't think they're actually worried
でも
別にららちゃん達は「おまじない」の結果を問題視しているわけじゃないんだ
about anyone performing the spell at all.
ららちゃん達は怪異とか　そんなのは多分
I think they probably
don't even believe in the supernatural.
そもそも信じてさえない　と思う
Yeah, I'm sure.
まあ　そうだろうな
It seems like they're more concerned
むしろそんなガセみたいな　いかがわしい「おまじない」が
with the fact that nonsense of
that sort is going around.
横行していること自体を問題視しているみたいで
They said they're trying to discover
誰かそんなものをはやらせているのかを　突き止めるんだって
who's spreading it.
No one's trying to spread it.
誰かがはやらそうとしたわけじゃないだろうし
突き止めたところで　広がった「おまじない」は
And even should they find someone,
もうそいつの責任ってわけじゃないだろう
now that it's spread, it isn't their responsibility.
That's just Rara-chan...
or rather, the Fire Sisters.
そこがららちゃん…ていうか
ファイヤーシスターズらしいところなんだけれど
llow Book Part  2
llow Book Part  1
ot Square Hut
I      II
of the Lands
II
Beginner
Intermediate
Advance
Scenario
Compilations
1     2
Golden Pagoda Tree
Poetry Archives
Chronicles Volume I
Chronicles Volume II
Chronicles Volume III
le of Tears
I        II
Collection   1
Collection   2
They seemed on the verge of saying
ららちゃん達は　誰かが目的をもって
that someone had deliberately spread
the spell for their own reasons.
「おまじない」をはやらせたんだと決めてかかってるみたいなんだよね
That sounds just like them...
らしいっちゃらしいな
Sheesh.
まったく　こりゃやっぱり
I'm gonna have to talk to Karen.
火憐とちゃんと話をしておく必要があるかもしれないな
It isn't something I have to get involved in...
別に放っておいてもよさそうだが
その案件には　「千石撫子」という実例が含まれているだけにデリケートだ
But given the chance
of Sengoku Nadeko getting involved, it's delicate.
K-Koyomi-oniichan?
こ…暦お兄ちゃん
It's nothing!
何でもない　大丈夫だよ　千石
I'm fine, Sengoku.
Anyway, Sengoku...
それと　なんつーか千石　お前ってそのほうがいいよな
You look better that way.
I mean your bangs.
や　だから前髪　外でもそうしてればいいのに
You should wear it like that outside.
B-But I'm embarrassed!
だ…だって　恥ずかしいし
でも　暦お兄ちゃんがそうしろって言うなら
But if you want me to...
I'll do my best.
頑張る
Yeah, doing your best is always good.
うん　頑張るのはいいことだ
Anyway, we're almost done with the Game of Life.
ところで　人生ゲームもそろそろ終わりそうだけど
千石　この後は何をする
What do you want to do after this?
ツイスターゲーム
Twister!
へえ　そりゃ知らないな
I don't know Twister.
どんなゲームだ　教えてくれよ
How do you play? Show me.
うん　教えてあげる
Okay, I'll show you...
I'll show your body.
その身体に
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
ははは　楽しみだなあ
I can't wait!
After that, Sengoku's mom
suddenly came home.
あの後　千石のお母さんが急に帰ってきた
I-I didn't tell them you were coming over!
こ…暦お兄ちゃんのことは秘密だったから
わ　わ　怒られる怒られる
She'll get mad! She'll get mad!
If she sees me dressed this way,
she'll think I'm a pervert...
こんな格好して　変態だと思われる
LEFT
どうしてだろう
I wonder why...
I think the fact that there was a problem at her workplace
何だかお母さんの職場でトラブルがあったお陰で
saved something important for me as a man.
僕の男の子として大切の何かが　救われたような気がする
本当は明日の予定だったけど　ま　いっか
It was supposed to be tomorrow, but eh...
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
This is Kanbaru Suruga!
神原駿河だ
Kanbaru Suruga...
神原駿河　主な武器は加速装置だ
Primary weapon, accelerator.
You're a cyborg?!
お前　サイボーグだったのか
ん　その声と突っ込みは阿良々木先輩だな
That voice and reply
could only be Araragi-senpai.
Yeah, but...
そうだけど
Hey, you're at home, right?
神原　お前今家だよな
Yes, I am.
うん　そうだ
Would you wait a minute, Araragi-senpai?
ああ　ちょっと待ってくれるかな　阿良々木先輩
I'll take my clothes off immediately.
すぐに裸になるから
Why?
何でだよ
何を言っているのだ阿良々木先輩
What are you talking about, Araragi-senpai?
電話でとは言え　阿良々木先輩と言葉を交わすのだぞ
It may be over the phone,
but I'm still speaking to you.
ならば裸になるのが礼儀と言うものだ
Thus, courtesy dictates that I must be naked.
Don't speak as if I've never heard of courtesy.
こっちがしかるべき常識を弁えていないみたいな言い方をするんじゃねえ
そしてことあるごとに機会を見つけて脱ごうとするな
And stop trying to find excuses to strip!
You've underestimated me.
甘いな　どうやら阿良々木先輩は私のスピードを軽く見ているようだ
I guess you don't understand how fast I really am.
I'm already naked!
すでに私は　全裸であるぞ
Already naked?
であるぞって
いよいよお前の変態度合いは僕の手に負えなくなってきたな　神原
Your perversion has finally gone further
than I'm willing to go, Kanbaru!
Oh, my...
おやおや　ここは私の家でここは私の部屋だぞ
This is my house, and this is my room.
No matter what I may or may not wear,
私がたとえどんな格好でいようと　それは私の自由のはずだ
that's a decision for me and me alone.
You're right.
確かに　悪かったな
Sorry.
家の外でマッパになったわけでもないのに　責めて悪かった
You weren't getting naked outside or anything.
I'm sorry for yelling.
No, as long as you understand, it's fine.
いや　分かってもらえればいいのだ
いくら解放感ある格好が好きな私でも　外にマッパになることなど
No matter how liberated I feel when naked,
I only go outside naked occasionally.
たまにしかない
You do it occasionally?!
たまにはあるのか
Like in a bath.
そりゃまあ　銭湯とかで
Or with the basketball team...
あとはバスケットボール部で
もう騙されねえぜ　合宿の時の風呂で　とか言うんだろう
You won't trick me this time...
I bet it was at the bath
during your team trip, right?
惜しい　合宿と言うところまでは正解だ
Close.
It was on our trip.
一年の夏　私の主催で行った全裸合宿と言う企画があってだな
During our first year, I led a nude training camp.
I hope your team gets banned!
廃部になれ
はは　阿良々木先輩　どうしたのだ
What's wrong, Araragi-senpai?
冗談に決まっているだろう
It was obviously a joke.
For you to believe such an obvious lie,
こんな戯言を信じるなんて
もしや本当に阿良々木先輩のほうが私よりいやらしいのではないか
you may be even more perverted than I am.
な…なんだと
Wh-What?
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
What's wrong, Kanbaru?
どうした　神原
I accidently forgot to close
the partition to my room...
Grand
mother
うっかり部屋のふすまを閉め忘れていて
And my grandmother came down the hallway.
お祖母ちゃんが廊下を通り過ぎていった
お祖母ちゃんがものすごく悲しそうな目で私を見て
She looked at me with sad eyes
無言で　歩くペースを落とすことなく通り去ってしまった
and passed me without missing a step!
Well, the granddaughter she raised
そりゃ　手塩にかけて育てた孫娘が　マッパで電話してたらなあ
was on the phone stark naked.
うあああ　私はもうおしまいだ
My life is over...
How can I ever talk to her again?
これから私はどんな顔をしてお祖母ちゃんと話せばよいのだ
Hey, Kanbaru.
あのさ　神原　ショック受けてるとこ悪いけど
Sorry to interrupt your emotional trauma,
ちょっと今日　予定外に受験勉強のスケジュールが空いちゃってさ
but I unexpectedly have the
day off from my test prep.
I know I promised to help clean
your room tomorrow.
本当は明日の約束だった　お前の部屋の片付け
But how about today?
今日やっちゃっていいか
Sure...
ああ　もちろん構わないぞ
That's fine.
Whatever day is best for you.
日付の都合はいくらでも阿良々木先輩に合わせよう
Then I'll be right there.
それじゃすぐ行く
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
ああ 兄ちゃんか 敵かと思った
Oh, it's you, Nii-chan?
I thought it was an enemy.
Do you even have enemies?
敵がいるのか お前には
まったく こんな人目につく場所であんな格好して
Jeez.
Doing handstands that way in public...
Don't you have any dignity?
はしたないにも程があるわ
お前はちょっとは思春期の女子らしい自意識を持て
You should act more like a girl
who's going through puberty.
ご近所で評判になったりしたらどうするんだ
What if you get a reputation?
I'm not sure I follow,
あれ なんだかわからないけれど
兄ちゃんは自分のことを棚上げにしている気配が
but I think you're trying to avoid
talking about yourself.
I'm not doing that at all.
そんなことは一切していない
What are you doing out here?
何してんだよ お前 こんなとこで
Community service.
奉仕活動だよ
Just a bit of volunteer work.
いわばボランティアだな
Volunteer work?
何がボランティアだ
得意げに横文字使ってんじゃねえよ 馬鹿
You don't even know what
that word means, idiot.
何すんだ 兄ちゃん 危ないだろ
What are you doing, Nii-chan?!
That's dangerous.
What's dangerous is what you're doing.
危ないのはお前達の活動だ
And what are you doing?
お前 今何してんだ
I told you, community service.
だから奉仕活動だって
Who do you think I am?
兄ちゃんはあたしを誰だと思ってるんだ
I don't know.
知らねえよ
Who are you, anyway?
誰なんだよお前は
Slayer of a thousand demons...
百鬼夜行をぶった斬る
Hell's guard dog, the Gumshoe Master!
地獄の番犬 デカマスターだ
うわ かっけー
How cool...
スーパークールに パーフェクト
Super-cool and perfect!
いや その姿勢
I guarantee that, if nothing else,
that pose is not at all cool.
少なくともクールではないが
そりゃあたし 燃える女だし
Well, I'm a brightly burning girl.
燃け死ね
Burn to death.
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
But I will admit that I enjoy the inherent humor
しかし  そんな格好悪い姿勢で
やたら格好いい台詞を言うという面白芸だけは
of saying cool things in that ridiculous pose.
認めてやってもいいな
I see, I see...
そうかそうか
じゃあ これからはこれをあたしの持ちネタとして使っていくことにしようかな
Then we'll make it a running gag of mine.
Okay, let's practice.
せっかくだから ちょっと練習してみようぜ
何でもいいから格好いいことを言ってみろ
Say something cool. Anything at all.
None shall pass without defeating me!
ここを通りたくばあたしを倒してからにしろ
Cooler than expected.
予想以上に面白い
And the reverse...
逆パターン
ここは任せて先に行け
Leave this to me. You go on ahead!
Anyway,
とにかくさ 今あたし
I'm busy with some stuff right now.
色々とやらなきゃいけないことがあって忙しいんだよ
Nii-chan, if you want to chat,
兄ちゃん 話なら夜にでも
家で月火ちゃんと一緒にするからさ
we'll do it tonight with Tsukihi-chan.
Will that work?
それで勘弁してくんない
Hello?
はい もしもし
Oh, yeah...
うん 兄ちゃん
Nii-chan...
It's okay.
大丈夫 これで本当にもうすぐ終わりそう
It looks like this really will be over soon.
Seems I'll have a heroic tale
夜に兄ちゃんに披露する話は
to tell tonight!
どうやらあたしの武勇伝になりそうだぜ
誰かそんなもん聞くか
Who'd listen to that?
The worst part of my day so far
お前が中三になってまで町中を逆立ちして歩いているって知ったことが
is finding out that you've nearly
finished middle school
今日の僕の最大の不幸だ
but still walk on your hands through the city.
Bye!
Hasta la vista!
アスタラビスター
Suruga's Grandmother
Ah...
Be kind to Suruga,
Koyomi-kun.
Suruga's Grandmother
Ah...
Be kind to Suruga,
Koyomi-kun.
K-Kanbaru?
か 神原
阿良々木先輩か
Is that you, Araragi-senpai?
ま 待て神原
Wait, Kanbaru!
Do not turn over right now...
今寝返りを打つな
今お前が寝返りを打つと大変なことになる
If you turn over, we'll have a big problem!
えっと
Oh, I apologize for this...
ああ こんな不細工な格好で失礼した
I'm embarrassed to be this way in front of you.
阿良々木先輩の前なのに 恥ずかしい
But for you to open the partition without knocking...
しかし ノックもなしでいきなりふすまを開けるなど
That isn't like the Araragi-senpai I know,
私の知る限り最高の人格者であるところの阿良々木先輩らしくないな
the paragon of virtue.
いや その
Um, well...
へこんでるお前を見たいと思って
I wanted to see you depressed...
ああ こんな見苦しいものでよければいくらでも見てもらって構わんぞ
If such an ugly thing satisfies you,
you're free to watch all you like.
Look long and well.
さあ 見るがいい これが神原駿河の真の姿だ
This is who Kanbaru Suruga truly is.
ありのままの神原駿河だ
With nothing at all concealed.
Well, that is...
いや
なんていうか その ごめん
Sorry.
悪かった 神原
Sorry, Kanbaru.
Let me take responsibility.
責任を取らせてくれ
Responsibility?
責任
What do you mean by responsibility, Araragi-senpai?
責任とは何だ 阿良々木先輩
Let's get married!
結婚しよう
Wh-Why marriage?
な なぜ結婚
いや 後ろ半分とはいえ 裸見ちゃったし
Well, even if it was just the back, I saw you naked.
You're skipping a few steps there.
段階をいくつか飛ばしている
By that logic,
その理屈だと
how many girls would you need to marry?
阿良々木先輩は一体どれほどの数の女性と結婚しなければならないのだろう
いや 人聞きの悪いことを言うなよ
That isn't a very nice thing to say!
Araragi-senpai,
阿良々木先輩
that's an extraordinarily attractive offer,
非常に魅力的な提案ではあるが
しかし 責任は取らなくてよい
but you don't need to take responsibility.
If you did that, Senjougahara-senpai
would get mad at me.
そんなことをしたら私は戦場ヶ原先輩から怒られてしまう
その代わりと言ってはなんだが
Instead, Araragi-senpai, I do have a request...
阿良々木先輩
一つだけお願いがあるのだが 聞いてもらえるかな
Would you fulfill it?
Sure, anything.
おう 何でも聞くぞ
For today, I'm your slave!
今日に限って 僕はお前の奴隷だ
I'd like to get dressed.
Could you wait in the hall?
服を着たいので 廊下で待っていてもらえるかな
Kanbaru, what's this?
神原 これって
ん ああ 部活のユニフォームだな
Oh, my team uniform.
COME
TO A
COMPLETE
STOP
I wondered where it had gone.
どこに行ったのかと思っていたのだが
And there it is.
そんなところにあったとは
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
へえ 練習用のユニフォームか
A practice uniform?
いや それは一年生の頃
No, it's a memento from my first year
全国大会出場を決めたときの記念品だ
when we made it to nationals.
ほら 裏返して内側を見てみてくれ
Turn it over and look inside.
その際のメンバーが
All of my teammates signed it.
寄せ書きをくれているだろう
Do you not understand the concept
of treasuring your memories?
お前には思い出を大切にするという概念がないのか
My memories are always in my heart.
思い出はいつも この胸の中に置いてある
That's a great line, but...
いい台詞だけど
Actually, I've only seen you play
そう言えば 実は僕ってお前が実際にバスケしているとこ
in a single basketball game...
一試合くらいしか見てないんだよな
Hey, Kanbaru.
そうだ 神原
Would you put this on?
ちょっとこれ着てみてくれないか
Sure.
構わんぞ
髪が伸びているから
I've grown out my hair, so I'll look
different than I did then.
当時と印象は大分違ってしまうと思うが
お前 髪伸びるのめちゃくちゃ早いよな
Your hair grows awfully fast...
Really?
ふむ そうか
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
I've heard normal hair grows at
普通 髪の伸びる速度って一ヵ月一センチくらいだって聞くけど
a rate of one centimeter per month.
お前のそれ 五センチは伸びてるよ
But yours has grown at least five.
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
Well, I'm really erotic.
まあ 私はエロエロだからな
She said it frankly!
ありていに言った
That's right.
そう 具体的にはぺぺロンチーノをいやらしい言葉だと
I'm so erotic,
aglio olio e peperoncino
I thought that "peperoncino"
長年勘違いしていたくらいエロエロだ
was a dirty word for years.
You should have realized that when you ate it!
食べた時点で気付け
I once misheard "family rate" as "family rape."
家族間通話を家族姦通派と思っていたり
Rape
DANGEROUS
SUBJECT
NO
ENTRY
First
I mean, I once misheard
"family rate" as "family hate."
あは　いや　家族間無料を家族感無量と思っていたのだ
NO
ENTRY
Hate
That doesn't really make it better!
アットホームに言い直しても駄目
And I remember recently thinking
そう言えば ブレスレットを『深呼吸しよう』的な意味だと
"bracelet" meant "let's take a breath."
勘違いしていたのも記憶に新しい
That isn't erotic at all.
It's just a misunderstanding!
EROTIC
それはエロとは関係ないただの勘違いだ
I said
『ドンマイ！』みたいな感覚で試合中に『ブレスレット！』と言って
"Bracelet" instead of "Don't worry" during matches,
赤っ恥をかいたものだ
getting really embarrassed.
I'll never forget my teammates' stunned expressions.
あのときのチームメイトのぽかーんとした顔は忘れられない
Stop it...
やめろ そのエピソードはリアルで痛過ぎる
That episode is too embarrassing!
Here...Well?
ほら どうだ こんな感じだ  阿良々木先輩
Something like this, Araragi-senpai?
When I wear this, I feel like I did back then.
こうしていると あの頃の気分になるな
Back then?
あの頃 現役時代のことか
When you played basketball?
N
O
E
N
T
R
Y
No, the nude training camp.
いや 全裸合宿
You're totally aware of it?!
自覚ありまくりかよ
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
The Glasses-Wearing Secretary
and
the Glasses-Wearing Prince
Watch for Falling Books
We can throw this one out...
これは捨てると
Watch for Falling Books
I guess it goes in the flammable trash.
燃えるゴミかな
Watch for Falling Books
Araragi-senpai,
阿良々木先輩 それは萌えるがゴミじゃない
that is not flammable trash.
腐ってはいても 必要なものだ
It may be rotten, but I need it.
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
しかし こういうのはどれも同じに見えちゃうよな
Watch for Falling Books
But these all look the same...
Can you tell the difference when you read them?
神原はきちんと区別をつけて読んでいるのか
Of course.
Watch for Falling Books
無論 人間知らないものは全て同じに見えるものだ
Any time one isn't familiar with something,
it all looks the same.
Watch for Falling Books
Knowledge and education
正しい評価を下すためには知識と教養が必要なのだ
are required to properly judge things.
そっか の割には
I see.
But even so...
The Glasses-Wearing Secretary
and
the Glasses-Wearing Prince
The Glasses-Wearing Secretary
and
the Glasses-Wearing Prince
The Glasses-Wearing Secretary
and
the Glasses-Wearing Prince
I guess they're all handsome.
Safety
First
結局 全部ハンサムなんだよな
I was just thinking you like 'em handsome...
いや 結局神原もハンサムが好きなんだなあって思って
Maybe you aren't really a big pervert.
お前 本当は大して変態じゃないんじゃないのか
Don't all girls like handsome guys?
ハンサムが好きって 女子なら当たり前じゃないか
So it's natural to enjoy seeing
handsome guys together.
そのハンサムが揃ってるのを見て楽しむのも当然だ
It's basically like an idol group, right?
Watch for Falling Books
つまりこれってアイドルグループみたいなもんだろう
P-Please don't use simplified examples!
わ わかりやすくたとえないでくれ
Watch for Falling Books
It's not as if you only like guys
who weigh more than 100 kg
体重が百五十キロを超えないとときめかないとか
Watch for Falling Books
加齢臭に興奮するとか
or are turned on by the smell of old men.
そういうことはないわけじゃん
U-Um, well...
い いや それはその
If you say that to me,
there's nothing else I can do...
Watch for Falling Books
阿良々木先輩からそんなことを言われたら私はもうおしまだ
脱ぐ
I'll strip!
今すぐ脱ぐから
I'll strip right now.
No, no, no, no.
いやいや 家の中でだらしない格好をするのもまた
When you think about it,
being underdressed
Watch for Falling Books
考えてみれば普通だしな
at home is actually pretty normal...
外でも銭湯くらいなんだろ
And even outside, it's only in a bath, right?
I'm sorry for all the things I've said.
今まで色々言って悪かったよ
I don't want you to apologize!
Watch for Falling Books
謝って欲しいんじゃない 阿良々木先輩
Araragi-senpai,
まずは私の話を聞いてくれ
listen to what I have to say.
And as you, yourself, said on the phone,
さっき電話で他ならねお前自身が言っていたように
maybe I'm the bigger pervert...
ひょっとしたら僕のほうがいやらしいんじゃないか
She fell into complete disarray.
That's... No!
Caution
ち 違う その辺りはたまたまそういう本が多いだけで
There's a difference in level
I just happen to have a lot of
books like that around there!
もっと奥の地層にはハードなBLもあるんだ
There's harder BL on a lower stratum!
I know that BL is more than just handsome guys!
ハンサムばかりがBLでないことくらい分かってる
ほら よく探してくれ
Keep looking!
Come on, Kanbaru.
おいおい 神原 探さなきゃないようなものは本当の自分とは
STOP
H
A
L
T
If you actually have to look for it,
it isn't really you...
STOP
H
A
L
T
STOP
H
A
L
T
STOP
H
A
L
T
STOP
H
A
L
T
STOP
H
A
L
T
STOP
H
A
L
T
H
A
L
T
H
A
L
T
H
A
L
T
H
A
L
T
か かくなる上は行為をもって身の潔白を示すしか ない
Now I have no choice but
to prove my innocence...
Araragi-senpai, prepare yourself!
阿良々木先輩 お覚悟
覚悟って
Prepare myself for what?
Don't worry...
大丈夫だ 痛いのは最初だけだ
It only hurts at first.
すぐに気持ちよくなる
It'll feel good soon.
Stop
P
E
D
S
T
R
I
A
N
Construction
P
E
D
S
T
R
I
A
N
Construction
P
E
D
S
T
R
I
A
N
Construction
P
E
D
S
T
R
I
A
N
Construction
阿良々木先輩も中々いい身体をしているではないか
You have a pretty nice body yourself.
I like these muscles.
私好みの筋肉だ
They feel great to touch!
実に触り心地がよい
Stop struggling...
こら 暴れるな パンツが脱がせにくいだろうが
It makes it harder to remove your underwear!
僕はこれから いついかなるテンションの時に八九寺を見かけたとしても
I swore then that
no matter how or when I encounter Hachikuji,
決して出会いがしらのセクハラ行為には及ぶまいと
I will never open the conversation
with sexual harassment.
そう誓ったのだった
Dialogue Script - Nisio Isin
4-Koma Illustrations - Haritama Hiroki
Preview
This is your master, Senjougahara Hitagi-sama.
I loved episode 1!
We're the fire sisters!
They say that lying is the first step towards stealing,
but doesn't that make it seem like lying is the lesser sin?
Let's do up your hair!
We're finally the
protagonists!
In fact, are there not a lot of crooks more vile than any thief?
What!
Huh?
What...?
Do you want to
cut something, Senjougahara?
Wouldn't stealing be the first step towards lying?
I beg of you!
Here's a haiku.
Is he okay?
Stolen from,
the heart abandoned,
meeting the swindler.
Next time! Karen Bee, Part 3!
Next Time
Karen Bee Part 3
Araragi Koyomi.
Seriously!
Show me
a mirror.
You will die a painful death.